那一刻
Moments...
这就是那一刻
This is one.
就在这儿，就现在，就是那一刻
This right here, right now,is definitely a moment.
泰萨？
Tessa?
下一秒什么事都有可能发生
Anything could happen next.
泰萨？-干吗？
- Tessa? - What?
你都没听我说话
You're not listening to me.
我听着呢
I am listening to you.
那我刚才说什么了？
What did I just say?
我没听
I wasn't listening to you.
我是说，今晚对你很重要
I'm saying this is a big night for you.
清单上的第一项
Number one on the list.
根本就没有什么清单
There is no list.
那你就做一份呗
You were gonna make a list.
我都没开始弄呢
I haven't started.
那就现在开始弄，赶紧的
Then start now. Go on.
好吧，那你喜欢哪个？我是一点都不在乎
Right. So, which one do you want? Because I really don't mind.
金发的那个
The blond one.
金发的？你确定吗？
The blond one? You're sure?
你想要他？我说过，我不在乎，不过……
You want him? Like I said, I don't mind. Just...
你可以选金发的那个
You can have the blond one.
只要你同意
Only if you're sure.
邹……怎么了？亲爱的
Zo...What, babe?
如果我跟那个谁那个了……我不知道，我会不会变成人渣？
If I do this with someone I don't know, does that make me a slag?
这能让你觉得自己还活着
It makes you alive.
那，你们经常去那家俱乐部吗？
So, that club, are you guys regulars there?
不是啊，你呢？
No. You?
有时候去，你知道的
Sometimes, you know.
对
Right.
还有什么别的地方可去吗？
Is there anywhere else we can go?
想来杯茶吗？或者咖啡？
Do you want a cup of tea? Or coffee?
好啊，都行
Sure, yeah. Either.
其实我们没有咖啡了
We haven't actually got any coffee.
好
Okay.
茶我也没找着
I can't find the tea.
我喝水就行了
Water's fine.
那，你最喜欢的……
So, what's your favorite...
你是想亲我吗？
Do you want to kiss me?
天呐，是啊
God, yeah.
天呐！没事
Jesus Christ! It's okay.
我滴个妈呀！没事的
Jesus bloody Christ! It's fine.
怎么了？
What happened?
这姑娘的脑袋……她的头套掉到我手上了
This girl's head... Her head came off in my hand!
你们笑什么呀？这有什么可笑的？
What are you laughing at? It's not funny.
差点把我尿吓出来，喔！
Scared the piss out of me.Whoo!
那，你是经常化妆出门吗？
So, do you often go out in disguise?
戴着假发什么的
The hair hat and all.
原先老戴，那会儿我病了
I got given it. I was ill.
那你现在好点了吗？
Are you better now?
好多了
All better.
哦
Oh.
不再多来点儿前戏啦？
Aren't we supposed to do that for a bit longer?
我现在就准备好了
I'm ready now.
等会儿，等会儿，你能先听我说吗？
Wait, wait. Can you just look at me for one second?
这是我的第一次
This is my first time.
喔~ 惊了
Wow. That's amazing.
很显然你不是
Obviously it's not yours.
别说了
Stop talking now.
唉，这样不行
Yeah, not like this.
怎么了？
What?
对不起，我不想
Sorry. Not gonna happen.
你是耍我呢吗？你大老远来了，还……
You're shitting me. You come this far, and...
真对不起
I'm sorry. Really.
随便吧
Whatever.
好吧
Okay.
我会爱你一生一世
I will love you till the end of time
我等了一百万年
I would wait a million years
答应我你会永远记得我的爱
Promise you'll remember that you're mine
亲爱的，透过这些眼泪
Baby, can you see through the tears?
你会看到我的爱胜过你以前那些傻逼娘们儿
Love you more than those bitches before
告诉我你不会忘，告诉我你永远记得
Say you'll remember, Say you'll remember
亲爱的
Baby, who
我会爱你直到永远
I will love you till the end of time
一夜好梦，冈斯特
Big dreams, gangsta
你说你必须离开这儿开启你的事业
Said you had to leave to start your life over
我说求你了，别走
I was like, no, please,
别走，我们不需要钱，我们会把日子过起来的
Stay here, we don't need no money, we could make it all work
但是他还是在礼拜天走了
But he headed out on Sunday
他说他礼拜一就回来
Said he'd come home Monday
我夜不能寐，一直等待着，期盼着，焦虑着
I stay up waitin', anticipatin', and pacing'
但他一心想着赚钱
But he was chasing paper
最后一次听到他的消息是他正沉湎于游戏之中
Caught up in the game that was the last I heard
我会爱你直到永远
I will love you till the end of time
等你一百万年
I would wait a million years
别忘了我的爱
Promise you'll remember that you're mine
亲爱的，透过我的眼泪
Baby, can you see through the tears?
你会看到我的爱胜过你以前那些傻逼娘们儿
Love you more than those bitches before
告诉我你不会忘，告诉我你会记得
Say you'll remember, Say you'll remember
亲爱的
Baby, who
我会爱你直到永远
I will love you till the end of time
爱你胜过你那些傻逼娘们儿
Love you more than those bitches before
告诉我你不会忘，告诉我你会记得
Say you'll remember, Say you'll remember
亲爱的
Baby, who
我会爱你直到永远
I will love you till the end of time
谢谢，谢谢你
Thanks. Thank you.
我不明白，我就是不明白
I don't understand it. I just don't get it.
你以前什么都跟我说
You always tell me everything.
我从来没有什么事都跟你说
I never tell you anything.
你为什么现在不说了呢？你昨晚都干吗了？
Why don't you start now? What were you doing last night?
继续问吧，爸爸，第15次一定能问出来
Keep asking, Dad.The 15th time is the charm.
嗨，我是卡洛琳，理查德的经纪人，咱们通过电话
Hi, I'm Caroline, Richard's producer.We spoke on the phone.
嗨，很高兴见到你
Hi. Good to meet you in person.
这位一定是泰萨
And this must be Tessa.
是我
That's me!
电梯坏了，她走楼梯没问题吧？
The lift's not working. Can she manage the stairs?
行啊，她没问题
Yeah, she'll be fine.
好
Okay.
泰萨·斯科特和她的爸爸来了
Tessa Scott and her father.
嗨，你们好。请坐。-你好
- Hi, guys. Take a seat.- Hello.
我们很高兴能被请到这来
Really pleased to be here.
是啊，我们是你的超级粉
Yeah, we're big fans.
很好，咱们只是聊聊天
Great. We'll just have a little chat.
尽量放松，我会帮你们把话题说完的，好吗？
Be as natural as you can and I'll help you through. Okay?
那，你从什么角度切入呢？
So, what's your angle going to be?
是从要死的女孩的角度呢
Is it the whole dying girl thing,
还是说你有什么别的切入点？
or do you have something original planned?
什么？
Sorry?
泰萨
Tessa.
我知道这是个沉重的话题，但是咱们试着让它积极点，好吗？
I know it's heavy stuff, but let's try to keep it upbeat. Yeah?
现在，我很荣幸地为大家介绍今天的嘉宾
And now I'm delighted to have as my guest in the studio
一个非常勇敢的姑娘，泰萨·斯科特
a very brave young lady indeed, Tessa Scott.
泰萨已经与白血病斗争了四年
Tessa's been living with leukemia for the past four years,
她和她的父亲将为我们讲述这个故事
and she's here with her dad to talk about it.
跟我们说说，你第一次意识到泰萨病了是什么时候？
Tell us, when did you realize that Tessa was first ill?
四年前
Four years ago.
她得了，我和泰萨的妈妈当时觉得
She had, well,we thought it was the flu,
她只是得了感冒
Tessa's mum and I.
但是这感冒老也不好
But the flu just wouldn't clear up.
验血报告证实了我们最坏的预测结果
The blood test confirmed our worst fears.
大夫跟我们说
The doctors told us they couldn't
他们对泰萨的病不抱任何希望
hold out any hope for her survival,
这就意味着让泰萨觉得
which brought us to the point where
自己除了化疗之外
Tessa felt like she had no choice
没有别的选择了
but to end her chemotherapy entirely.
泰萨，你后来选择了放弃治疗
Tessa, you chose to give up the treatment.
这对于一个17岁的孩子来说是个重大决定
That's a big decision for a 17-year-old.
我想如果……
If I may...
参与积极的治疗
The more aggressive treatments,
仅仅能够稍微……
they would have only slightly
延长泰萨的生命
prolonged Tessa's life.
还有其他的治疗方法
There are other ways to maintain her health.
爸……-比如说，有研究证明……
Dad... - For example, studies have shown
好的营养品能够将体内的白血球系统重新平衡
that good nutrition can rebalance a system entirely.
这就是我们来这的真正原因，让大家提高对白血病的认识，而且……
That's why we're here really, to raise awareness, and...
爸……怎么了？
Dad... What?
他知道总会有那么一天
He's gonna have to stop sometime.
哪么一天，泰萨？
Stop what, Tessa?
他知道最后我还是会死
He knows it's gonna happen.
但是他从来没有放弃希望
But he can't stop hoping that it won't.
如果我继续化疗
It's true that if I kept going with the chemo,
确实能让我多活几年
I'd probably live a bit longer.
但是那让我感觉太糟糕了
But it made me feel so bad.
在我死前还有些事要做
And there are things I want to do before I die.
什么事？
Things?
我列了个清单
Yeah. I've got a list.
哦，你爸爸没提到过这个
Oh. Your dad didn't mention that.
那是因为他不知道
That's 'cause he doesn't know about it.
大部分都是违法的
Most of what's on it is illegal.
我都不敢问了
I'm almost scared to ask.
我昨天晚上差点和人发生性关系
Well, I nearly had sex last night,
技术上而言，这肯定是犯法的
which isn't actually technically against the law of course,
但是那感觉太差了，那哥们真应该为此被抓起来
but it was so crap the guy should be arrested anyway.
好了，我想我们的结束时间快要到了
Okay, I think that's all we've got time for.
我下一个计划是吸毒
Next I'm planning to take drugs.
你能给我介绍一种毒品吗？
Do you have any advice which ones?
别说了，泰萨
That's enough, Tessa.
很令人惊讶啊
Very amusing.
性，毒品和摇滚乐
Sex and drugs and rock 'n' roll.
女士们先生们，我想你们也有同感
Ladies and gents,I think you'll agree
这是一个勇敢面对生活的姑娘
there is a young lady taking life by the horns.
非常感谢，泰萨和她的父亲
Thank you very much,Tessa and her dad.
谢谢你
Thank you.
接下来是天气情况，今儿早上的大风
And now the weather.Squally this morning,
会一直持续到下午，
rounding up this afternoon and clearing
而本周接下来几天会放晴
for the rest of the week.
她出去了。-没有
She's out.-No.
爸
Dad...
等等
Wait.
没睡好？
Bad night?
没事儿
There's no such thing.
你好啊，亲爱的，请进
Hello, darlings. Come on in.
嘿，妈妈
Hi, Mum.
你怎那么颓啊
You look stressed.
都赖她。我四点来接他们
Blame her. Back at 4:00.
这是个新把戏，我能把硬币变没
It's a new trick, Mum. I can make a coin disappear.
你想看吗？
Do you want to see it?
不想，亲爱的，我想先喝点咖啡
No, darling. Not before coffee.
喝咖啡之前我什么都不想干。去给你姐姐看吧
Nothing before the coffee. Show your sister.
她对我这些戏法从来都不感兴趣。
She's never interested. She doesn't care.
她肯定感兴趣
I'm sure she does.
我真没兴趣
I really don't.
要不你去看看动画片什么的吧
Why don't you go and watch CBeebies or something?
就因为我才九岁
Because I'm nine.
我听见你在广播里做的节目了
I heard you on the radio.
你有男朋友了
You met a boy.
泰萨，你得跟我保证一定要戴套
Tessa, promise me you'll always use a condom.
我知道那小橡胶套挺讨厌的
I know the smell of rubber can be off-putting,
但是不戴的话会得淋病的
but, then, so is gonorrhea.
别说了，你搞得我很恐慌
Please stop. My panic attack is having a panic attack.
不要滥交
And don't have casual sex.
是么？
Really?
是的，亲爱的
No, darling.
你一定一定要很努力才行
You must always, always try as hard as you can.
我想去纹个身
I've got to get a tattoo.
我也想纹
And I want one and all.
纹满全身的那种
Over my whole body, of myself.
我想再长高点，胸部再大点
And taller, with bigger tits.
怎么了？
What's up?
他真是个大骗子
He's such a bloody liar.
谁呀？-斯科特
Who? Scott.
他说他在这有个摊位
Said he had a stall here.
我们来这儿就为这个？
Is that why we came?
真不敢相信他居然放我鸽子
I can't believe he'd blow me off.
是我让他活得还有点意思
I gave him the ride of his life.
邹，-卑鄙的东西
Zo... -Wanker.
小邹……-干吗？
Zo... -What?
他在那呢
He's right there.
嘿，帅哥
Hey, handsome.
怎么样？
What's up?
我不知道，取决于你
I don't know. You tell me.
就看你怎么表现了
Or better yet, show me.
嘿
Hey.
你好吗？
How are you?
我挺好
I'm fine.
那天晚上把你晾在那我真是……
I know I left you hanging the other night and I just wanted...
没事，是我不对
No, it was my fault.
什么？
What?
我就是……我应该多来点前戏……
I just...I could've been a bit more...
她跟你说了
She told you.
什么？
What?
是你说的，是不是？你跟他说了我的事
You did, didn't you? You told him about me.
你不应该说出去
Shouldn't have done that.
泰萨，等等
Tessa, wait!
泰萨
Tessa!
嘿，错过午饭了
Hey. You missed lunch.
你自己吃吧
You eat it.
你这是干吗呢？
What are you doing with all this?
隔壁在院子生火呢
There's a bonfire in the garden next door.
别扔了，求你别扔了
Don't do that. Please don't do that.
你要是不想要这些东西给我
If you don't want these things, I do.
那是在西班牙，你当时在恢复期
That's Spain. You were in remission.
有个小子冲我吹口哨，你还挺高兴
A boy whistled at me, and you took that.
你说我应该永远记得第一个对我吹口哨的人
Said I'd never want to forget my first whistle.
是啊
Yeah.
但是我不想记得
But I do.
你这是干吗呀？
What are you doing?
你不介意吧？
Do you mind?
无所谓
Feel very free.
我是亚当
I'm Adam.
你是泰萨吧
And you're Tessa.
搬过来之后老能在附近看见你
I've seen you around,since we moved here.
我本来想自我介绍来着，但是……
I meant to introduce myself, but...
这不是情书
They're not love letters.
这跟我没关系
It's none of my business.
我是说，我没有被谁甩了之类的事
I'm just saying. I didn't get dumped or anything.
我也没那么想
I wouldn't have thought so.
我还有别的东西要烧
Anyway,I've got more stuff to burn.
行啊，烧吧
Cool, whack it on.
这个也得烧
This is going.
烧了更好，穿着这个裙子很危险
Probably best. That's a dangerous dress.
你没事吧？
Are you okay?
泰萨？
Tessa?
好了，别动，别动，你刚才晕过去了
All right, don't move. Don't move. I think you fainted.
你有糖尿病吗？
Are you diabetic?
要不要吃糖？
Do you need sugar?
我这有汽水
Have some of this.
汽水都没气儿了
It's flat.
你可真难缠
You're tough to please.
你这口气就跟想和我上床似的
You say that like it's a bad thing.
好了，很好，不尴尬，一点都不尴尬
Okay, excellent. Not embarrassed, not embarrassed at all.
对，没事，对吧？
No, it's cool, all right?
我是说，我还从来没遇到过这种情况呢
I mean, I've never had that effect on someone before.
没事
I kind of like it.
这花园真漂亮
This is a nice garden.
谢谢，这都是我弄的，我想让我妈妈高兴
Thanks. It's kind of my thing. It keeps my mum happy.
你爸呢？
How about your dad?
只有我跟我妈我们俩
It's just the two of us.
我得回去了。-好，你要我扶你吗？
I should get home. -All right. You need help?
又不远
It's not exactly far.
那，下回你要是还有什么要烧的话……
So, anytime you've got something to burn...
或者我想在谁面前晕倒的话……
Or I just want to pass out in front of someone...
你可以来找我
You know where to come.
是啊，我知道
Yes, I do.
泰萨死了之后，咱们能去度假吗？
When Tessa dies, can we go on holiday?
卡尔，你怎么这么说话啊
Cal, that's an awful thing to say.
上次去西班牙我都不记得了
I don't even remember going to Spain.
那都多久以前的事儿了，我都怀疑咱们到底去没去过那
It was so long ago,it might not even be true.
卡尔，别说了，回你房间去
Cal, that's enough.Go to your room.
爸。-怎么了？
Dad...-What's wrong?
出去！
Get out!
我说错什么了？
What did I say that was wrong?
真让人想不通
It's all very confusing.
那就别想了
No, it's not.
今天都是你的
This is your day.
什么意思？
And what does that mean?
你想干什么我都陪着你
That I'll do whatever you want.
再买点东西行吗？
Buy more things?
当然了
Sure.
你哪来的钱？
Where does the money come from?
姐有信用卡
A credit card.
现在买，回头再付账
Buy now, pay later.
或者，知道么，不付也行
Or you know, not.
看着点你那飞机，差点捅着人眼睛
Watch where you're flying. You almost poked the guy's eye out.
我真希望自己也能飞一飞
I wish I could fly for real.
是吗？
Yeah?
太棒啦！
Amazing!
这是我玩过的最好玩的了！
That was better than the best thing ever!
我能再玩一次吗？
Can I go again?
我觉得应该让你姐姐玩一次了
I think it's your sister's go.
没事，我看看就行了
I'm good, I'm just watching.
真的吗？-对
Are you sure? -Yeah.
她得病了，不能玩这种东西
She's sick. She can't do this kind of thing.
好吧，小兄弟，咱们再来一次
All right, mate, well, let's get you hooked up again.
要不然，那什么
Actually, you know what?
我也玩一次得了
I will have a crack.
准备好了吗？-准备好了！
Ready? -Ready.
泰萨，我觉得你还是不应该玩这个
Tessa, I don't know if this is a good idea.
她没事吧？
Is she okay?
她没事
She's fine.
她只是不想停下来而已
She just doesn't want it to end.
那不是你的钱
It wasn't your money.
她迟到了
She's late.
你听见我说话了吗？
Do you hear what I'm saying?
她说她肯定来的
She promised she'd come.
泰萨
Tessa...
你要让卡尔把所有东西都退回去吗？
Do you want Cal to return everything?
为什么要惩罚他呢？
Why should he be punished?
你这是干吗呀？
What are you doing?
这是你那张清单上的事吗？
Is this to do with your list?
我根本没列清单
I don't have a list.
你跟电台主播说你列了张单子
You told that radio guy you had a list.
那是一个傻逼
He was a knob.
是啊，他是挺傻逼的
Yeah, he was a knob.
你宁愿跟一个傻逼说实话都不愿意跟我说
You were still more honest with him than you are with me.
你让我心里怎么想？
How do you think that makes me feel?
我才不在乎你怎么想呢
I don't give a crap how you feel.
她不会来了，咱们先去吧
She's not coming.Let's do this.
泰萨，我现在要给你打麻醉剂
Tessa, there'll be a slight pinch and burn,
会有点疼，忍着点，好吗？
then the anesthetic will kick in. All right?
很好
Good.
现在，我要把它轻轻晃动几下
Now, I wiggle up and down
管子会穿透插入点的皮下组织
to break the tissue around the insertion point.
她会感到胸腔有被拉扯的感觉
She may feel a slight tugging across the chest,
但是当管子从接口处分离的时候
but once the line detaches from the cuff,
它就会滑走
it will simply slide away.
现在，我可以重新插入导管了
Now, of course I can reinsert the catheter
你确定要重新开始化疗吗？
should you wish to recommence your treatment.
现在改主意还来得及
I'm saying you can change your mind.
不改了
I won't change my mind.
父亲怎么说？
Dad?
她不会改主意了
She won't change her mind.
好吧
All right then.
按住
Hold that for me.
好姑娘
Good girl.
要不你直接拍我屁股得了
Do you want to slap my rump?
什么？不
What? No.
那就别把我当匹马那样跟我说话
Then don't talk to me like I'm a horse.
好吧
Yes.
抱歉
Sorry.
嘿，完事了，都弄完了
Hey, it's done now. It's done.
你知道都应该注意哪些症状吗？
You know what to look out for?
知道，发冷，发热，脖子僵硬，头疼
Yeah. Chill, fever,stiff neck or headache.
出汗，出血，体力流失
Drainage, bleeding,loss of strength.
很好
You're good.
感谢你的帮助
Thanks for all your help.
她看上你了
She likes you.
得了吧
I doubt that.
真的，你心跳都加快了
I mean it. You're bang in there.
你真应该约她出来或者干点别的什么的
You should definitely ask her out or something.
泰萨，泰萨，等等，我在这儿，我这就下来，别走
Tessa! Tessa, wait, I'm here.I'm coming. Stay there.
哦，天呐，我错过手术了吗？我出来得还算及时啊
Oh, God, did I miss it? I left on time.
主要是堵车误在路上了
But there was this insane traffic.
我出来得真不晚，我就是……
I definitely left on time.I just...
是啊，随便你怎么说吧
Sure, whatever.
泰萨
Tessa...
我不在乎
I don't care.
哦，别这样
Oh, don't be like that.
那你想让她哪样啊？
How do you expect her to be?
抱歉，这跟你有什么关系？
I'm sorry, this has what to do with you?
你真想知道吗？-是啊我想……
Is that a serious question? -Yes, it's a serious...
行了
Enough.
你们俩都挺操蛋的
You both suck.
一个是癌症观察者
One of you is this cancer obsessive,
另外一个连面儿都不肯露
and the other can't even face showing up
这就够了
at the hospital, which is fine,
我懂了
I get it.
但是你们俩我都不需要
But neither of you are what I need.
你们只是在浪费我的时间
You're just wasting my time.
我是说……-你甭说了
All I'm saying... -This is not gonna be all you say.
我是说……-根本不是那么回事儿
All I'm saying is...-There'll be another thing.
我的意思是，你不用整天围着我转
All I'm saying is, you don't have to stay in on my account.
你应该出去多跟你的朋友们玩一玩
You could go out and see your friends more often.
这就是我想说的。-好吧，好吧
And that's all I'm saying.-Okay. Okay.
我刚吸了毒
I've just taken drugs.
很好，来见见我妈妈
Excellent. Have you met my mum?
嗨
Hi.
我只是吃了迷幻蘑菇，那是纯天然的
Mushrooms is all I did, which are natural.
也不是完全不合法
If not strictly legal.
我的朋友本来想买些克他命
My friend did buy some ketamine,
但是她觉得那个卖毒品的人太讨厌了
but she thought the dealer was a bit skanky,
所以我们用迷幻蘑菇代替了
so we've gone with the shrooms instead.
我先进屋了
See you inside.
很好
That went well.
我觉得也是
I thought so.
你吃了多少？
How much did you take?
没多少
Not much.
我不知道，我对那些东西没什么了解
I don't know, I'm not really that clued up on the stuff.
是啊，我也不懂
Yeah, me neither.
听着，我开车带你兜兜风，让你也醒醒毒
Look, I'll drive you somewhere. Keep you out of trouble.
我不知道药效多久才能发作
I'm not sure how long it takes to kick in.
那就是发作了吧
About that long.
Seven shooting stars in one night
The water and sand in our eyesight
The rocks in our hands
preparing for flight
The lack of sleeping
but it's all right
And it's all
And it's all right
别害怕
Don't be afraid.
什么？怎么了？
What? -What?
你刚才说什么？
What did you say?
好了，咱们可以在这儿待会儿
All right,we could hang out here.
周围没人，你们可以尽情地疯
There's no one around,so you guys can go crazy.
我不想疯
I don't want to go crazy.
我根本就不想疯
I don't have to go crazy at all.
我爬到上边来就行了
I'll just be up here.
你干吗呀？
What are you doing?
好了，下来
All right. Get down.
下来，别爬车顶。-我不
Come on, get down, off the roof.-No.
求求你，下来吧
Come on, get down. Please.
干吗？你要上来抓我？
Why? Are you gonna make me?
不是，我就跟你说，下来
No, I'm just gonna tell you. Get down.
好吧，我下来。-谢谢你
Fine. All right? -Thank you.
真烦人
Harshing my buzz.
泰萨去哪了？
Where's Tessa?
什么？
What?
咱们得跟着她
We gotta go after her.
谁知道她往哪走了？
We didn't see which way she went.
咱们得赶紧找到她
We need to find her. Now.
她会回来的，我说，这没什么大不了的
She'll come back. I mean, it's no big thing.
咱们刚进林子，不会有危险的
We're just out here. There's no danger.
有，有危险
Yes, there is.
为什么？邹逸
Why? Zoey...
这时候我真不该告诉你
This time I'm really not supposed to tell you.
告诉我什么？
Not supposed to tell me what?
泰萨
Tessa!
我发现一好东西
I've discovered something.
你没事吧？你自己能下来吗？
Are you okay? Can you get down?
我不想下去
I don't want to.
好吧，等着
All right, just wait.
抓紧了，我这就来
Just hold on, I'm coming.
要抓紧哦
Just hold on.
泰萨
Tessa...
你快下来吧，求你
You need to come down now, please.
我扶着你咱俩一块下去
You need to let me help you climb down.
我想跟你说点事
I'm going to tell you something.
但是你得保证不告诉别人，行吗？
But you have to promise not to tell anyone, okay?
在这我的病全好了
I'm not sick here.
我再也不会得病了
I'm not sick anymore.
我得待在这片林子里
I just need to stay here in this wood.
我需要远离现代社会和所有那些玩意儿
I need to keep away from the modern world and all its gadgets
这样我就不会病了
and then I won't be sick.
你要是愿意的话可以跟我在一起
You can stay with me if you want.
你要是愿意的话我会很高兴的
I'd like it if you did.
咱们可以建个房子，修条小路
We'll build things,shelters and tracks.
还可以种菜
We'll grow vegetables.
咱们会很安全
We'll be safe.
泰萨……-不
Tessa...-No.
什么也别说
Please. Don't say anything.
泰萨
Tessa?
干吗？
What?
你要是死了我还是你弟弟吗？
Will I still be a brother when you're dead?
我不会走远的
I'll still be around.
你会在我周围盘旋吗？
Are you going to haunt me?
你要是不愿意我就不盘旋了
Not if you don't want me to.
我可能会有点害怕
Just I might be a bit scared.
护士来了，爸爸说你要准备好了就下来
The nurse is here. Dad says come down when you're ready.
蛋糕好吃吗？
Enjoying your cake?
嗯
Mmm.
很好吃，谢谢你，泰萨
It's lovely.Thank you, Tessa.
我叫菲利帕
I'm Philippa.
你看上去不太舒服
You don't look like you're feeling too good.
你舒服吗？
Would you be?
不是针对你的，她上礼拜跟上一个护士也这样
Take nothing personally. She was rude to last week's nurse, too.
好像叫肖恩
Sian, I think she was called.
别假装不记得她的名字，爸爸
Don't pretend you've forgotten her name, Dad.
你还邀请人家留下吃晚饭呢，被人给撅了
You asked her to stay for supper. She said no.
我去隔壁房间
I'll be next door.
他没有一件事做对的
He does everything wrong.
你有什么感觉？
How does that make you feel?
他让我觉得可笑
It makes me laugh.
你知道么，有一个帮助组织
You know,there are support groups.
在那里你能认识很多跟你一样情况的人
Places you can meet people in the same position as you.
我去过一次
I went to one of those.
认识一个叫安吉拉的酷妞
Met a cool girl called Angela.
那你为什么不跟她聊聊呢？
So why not talk to her about all this?
因为她死了
Because she died.
那是我最后一次犯那种错误
Last time I make that mistake.
完了吧？
Are we done?
嘿
Hey.
你不用那么看着我
You don't have to look at me like that.
我只是快死了而已，又不传染
I'm just dying. It's not contagious.
你今天感觉怎么样？
How are you feeling today?
我能骑一圈吗？
Can I come for a ride?
你总是用问题回答问题吗？
Do you always answer a question with another question?
你觉得别扭吗？
Does that annoy you?
出了点小毛病很棘手
Bit tricky to ride this at the minute.
我觉得我应该把发动机拆下来，该清洗了
I thought I'd strip the engine down, give it a clean.
那你现在装不回去了
And now you can't put it back together.
你什么意思？我能啊，没问题的
What do you mean? I can, no trouble.
如果这个小玩意不重要的话
Just so long as this bit wasn't important.
你刚才说咱们要去哪来着？
Where did you say we were going again?
我没说
I didn't.
什么？
What?
横穿全国的徒步旅行。-真不错
A good long cross-country hike. -Excellent.
我的最大问题就是精力无处释放
Because my big problem is too much energy to burn.
就在那
Nearly there.
值得来一趟吧？
It's worth it, yeah?
值了
Yes.
你和你妈到底怎么回事？
So, what's the story with you and your mum?
我爸爸去年出车祸死了
My dad died last year.He was hit by a car.
那时候我刚考上大学，本可以住宿舍，但只能延期了
I had a place at college, but I had to defer it.
还是应该上学去
You should still go.
我不知道，我有点……
I don't know. I kind of...
我不知道我有没有做好心理准备
I'm not sure I was ready for it anyway.
你害怕吗？
Are you afraid?
有时候怕
It comes and goes.
好多人都觉得如果你得了病
Most people think that when you're sick
你就会变得无所畏惧
you become fearless and brave,
其实根本不是
but you don't.
大部分时间都会觉得被一个精神病人追着跑
Most of the time it's like being stalked by a psycho,
随时都会被击倒
like I might get shot any second.
有时候，有那么几个小时我就会忘了这些
Sometimes I forget about it for hours.
什么让你忘了这些呢？
What makes you forget?
咱俩在森林里那颗大树上的时候
When I was with you in the wood,
那整个下午我都没怎么想那些
I didn't think about it for the whole afternoon.
看着我
Look at me.
我现在就没想
I'm not thinking about it now.
那你为什么不想走？
So, why don't you want to go?
我什么也不该说
I shouldn't have said anything.
精灵已经从神灯里出来了
Genie's out of the bottle now.
这是谁的聚会？
Whose party is it?
不知道
I'm not sure.
你没被邀请吗？
You didn't get invited?
没有
That's not really how it works.
但是你所有的朋友都去了？
But all your mates are going?
我猜是吧
I guess, yeah.
我那不还没修完车呢么
I just haven't done this stuff in a while.
咱俩一块进去
Makes two of us.
嘿，你想在这儿玩吗？
Hey, so, do you just want to hang out here?
我去拿点喝的
I'll get us something to drink.
好
Yeah.
要不跟我一块来吧？
Or come with me?
我跟你一块去
I'll come with you.
嘿，他在那呢
Hey, there he is!
嘿，朋友们
Hi, guys...
抱歉认错人了
Sorry to bother you,
我们的朋友
it's just we used to know someone
跟你这个朋友长得很像
who looked just like your friend here.
我叫泰萨，很高兴认识你
I'm Tessa. It's nice to meet you.
如果你能让他从这出去
If you're the one that got him out of the house,
那就也很高兴认识你
it's good to meet you, too.
大学怎么样？
How's college?
你甚至都不用假装什么都学
You don't even have to pretend to learn anything.
你也应该试试。是啊，我会的，有机会吧
You should try it. Yeah, I will, sometime.
你还喝这个吗？
Are you drinking this?
喝呀……
Yeah, actually...
嗯，我觉得挺好，突然闯到一个聚会上去
Yeah, it's good, I think, just to pop in to parties like that.
我不想因为待得太久而招人讨厌，你呢？
Don't want to outstay a welcome, do you?
你在聚会上还挺受欢迎，你应该多出来参加这种聚会
You got a pretty big one there. You should get out more.
他们并不介意我进去，是吧？
Well, then they wouldn't care when I walked in, would they?
那个姑娘欺负过你？
Did that girl hurt you?
别的方式欺负的我
Other way round.
她一拳打到我下巴上了，可疼了
I caught her fist a good one with my chin,
然后我就用鼻子挡她的膝盖
then whacked her right in the knee with my nose.
你还真得小心点
You need to be careful.
用不着
No, I don't.
就是这么回事
That's the thing.
你到家了
Here you go then.
你这是什么意思？
How do you mean?
你到家了。不，瞎说，不行
This is you. No, bollocks, no way.
我送你到家门口
I'll walk you to your door.
不用了吧？-当然用，没事
Are you sure? -Yeah, of course, no trouble.
看
See?
谢谢你
Thank you.
嘿
Hey.
你好
Hello.
你掉了五块钱
You dropped a fiver.
什么？
What?
五块钱，你掉的
That fiver. You dropped it.
那不是我的
That's not mine.
我看见它从你兜里掉出来的
I saw it come out of your pocket.
真得吗？-可不
Really? - Yeah.
因为我当时正往那看呢
'Cause I was looking.
好吧，谢谢
Okay, well, thanks.
太牛逼了！绝对的
That was so cool. It totally was.
我们像真正的窃贼一样牛逼！你那双勾人的眼睛太厉害了
We rock as criminals. That flirty eye thing you were doing.
你拿卡的时间也恰到好处
What about you nipping in there with the perfect timing?
那咱们现在干吗？
So now what?
现在咱们去取点钱然后去个聚会
Now we get some cash out and party.
用这卡取？-是的
With the card? -Right.
好吧，密码是什么？
Okay. What's the number?
你什么意思？
What do you mean?
你没看见密码吗？
Didn't you see the number?
没有哇，我当时正忙着用眼睛电他呢
No, I was doing the flirty eye thing.
我只管拿卡
I was nipping in there.
咱俩这盗贼当的太屎了
We suck as criminals.
也许这样最好。那哥们看上去没事
Probably best.The guy seemed all right.
要不咱俩试试再把卡还给他
Maybe we should try and give his card back.
怎么还？
And how are we going to do that?
希望我没打断你们，回来！
Not interrupting anything,am I? Get...
泰萨……干吗？
Tessa...What?
那张卡。-卡怎么？
The card. -What about it?
还给他
Give it back to him!
斯科特老耍酷，我知道他对我着迷了
Scott plays it cool.I know he's crazy about me.
你怎么知道？
How'd you know?
因为他是男的
Because he's a guy.
我信你
I'll take your word for it.
那你说他昨天晚上干吗不给我打电话？
So, why didn't he call me last night?
小邹，有个事我想跟你说
Zo, there's something I need to tell you.
咱先把这一票干完
Let's get this done first.
记住，在商店里偷东西靠得全是自信
Remember, shoplifting's all about confidence.
抬头挺胸，拿起来放进包里
Walk tall, pick and pocket.
进去之后咱俩分开行动
In there, we go in separate.
为什么不能在一起？
Why not together?
在一块更可以，走吧
More suspicious. Go on.
好吧
Right.
泰萨？泰萨·斯科特？
Tessa? Tessa Scott?
不，不是我
No. Sorry.
就是你
It is you.
你还记得我们俩吗？高中的时候
Don't you remember us? From school.
哦，是啊
Oh, yeah.
你11岁的时候转学了，是吧？
You left in Year 11,didn't you?
十岁
Ten.
你现在怎么样了？还在进行化疗吗？
So how's it going? Are you still having all that treatment?
不治了
Not anymore.
这么说你好点了？
So you're better?
没有
No.
你们想干吗呀？
What do you two want?
嘿，邹逸，你帮她购物吗？
Hi, Zoey. You helping her shop?
走吧？-好
Are you ready to go? -Yeah.
你跟斯科特·雷蒙德约会，是真的吗？
Is it true you've been seeing Scott Redmond?
关你屁事？- 你认识他吗？
What's it to you? -Do you know him?
行了，走吧
All right, let's go.
大家都认识他
Everybody knows him.
半小时前他跟我姐姐出去了
He went out with my sister for about half an hour.
是么？
Is that right?
我还得去选我葬礼的邀请卡呢
I have to go collect the invites for my funeral.
真的？-是啊
Really? -Yeah.
我还得去整理我的悼词
I also need to sort out the readings.
确保那不是一首破诗，这些都得在我死前弄完
Make sure it's not that bloody poem. It's been done to death.
放开我
Let go of me.
她们都是傻逼，小邹，她们什么都不知道
They're idiots, Zo. They don't know anything.
我知道
I know.
我得去找他去
I have to go find him.
现在？
NOW?
是啊，对不起，我得走了
Yeah. I'm sorry. I need to go.
嘿！
Hey!
还有一个，把她也抓住！
Another one! Stop her too!
抓住了
Gotcha.
坐下
Sit down.
把兜里东西都掏出来
Empty your pockets.
好了，我管这些叫证据，你知道么？
Well, I'd call that evidence, wouldn't you?
姓名，住址，父母的电话
Name. Address. Parents' phone numbers.
别给我爸打电话
Don't call my dad.
我们有两个选择
We have a choice.
要不然给你爸打电话，要不然就报警
We can call him, or we can call the police.
报警吧，每次都是报警
The police, every time.
我跟门外那个人说我能处理这个，不过如果你……
Now, I told that guy out there I'd handle it, and if you...
听着……
Listen...
这是一个植入式经脉输液口
This is a portacath.
化疗透析用的
It's an access disk for medical treatments.
我得了急性淋巴细胞白血病
I have acute lymphoblastic leukemia.
请你把衣服穿好
Please put your shirt back on.
你知道什么叫急性淋巴细胞白血病吗？
Do you know what acute lymphoblastic leukemia is?
不，恐怕我不知道
No, I'm afraid I don't.
就是癌症
It's cancer.
那我还是得给你爸打电话
I still have to call your dad.
还有你，你什么借口啊？
And you, what's your excuse?
她都偷什么了？
What did she take?
蓝条家庭验孕棒
One Clearblue Home Pregnancy Test.
这也在你的列表上吗？在商店偷东西？
Was this on the list? Shoplifting?
你这是干吗呀？泰萨？
What are you doing, Tessa?
你这是干吗？
What are you doing?
尽我所能，尽快实现我这些愿望
As much as I can.As fast as I can.
我希望你停下来
I wish you'd stop.
你愿意让我下半辈子
You'd prefer I spend the rest of my life
裹着毯子蜷在沙发里
huddled in a blanket on the sofa,
头垂在你的肩膀上吗
with my head on your shoulder.
是，我愿意，你要责怪我吗？
Yeah, I would.Can you blame me?
是的，我愿意
Yes, I would.
我的意思是，我的意思是我喜欢强壮的女人
My point is... Well, my point is, I like a strong woman.
你一直喜欢被抱上床的感觉吧
You've always wanted to be carried to bed.
我一直就想被人抱上床
I have always wanted to be carried to bed.
我不喜欢什么呢，把一个
What I don't do, is bring to a mate's party
公认的，完美的，显形的，年轻精灵术士带到哥们的聚会上去
an, admittedly perfectly formed, young pixie warlock.
她可不是什么术士
Yeah, she's isn't a warlock.
我意思是，你不能到处去
I mean you can't just go around
找人打架
starting fights every which way
而且到处砸东西吧（手机：往右看）
and shaking things up like that.
显然你可以那么干
Apparently you can.
你到这来干吗？
What are you doing here?
我都跟踪你一整天了
I've been stalking you all day.
我才刚刚鼓起勇气现身的
I only just now plucked up the courage to reveal myself.
是吗？
Really?
不是
No.
我爸在绿色食品店买东西呢，他可能会开车经过这儿
My dad's in the health food store.He could drive past.
能在见到你的朋友们真好
It's nice to see your mates again.
是啊，永远那么兴奋
Yeah. Always a pleasure.
好了，怎么回头见吧
Well, I'll see you around, maybe.
好的
Sure, yeah.
我知道你还看着我呢
I know you're looking.
我没看
I'm not looking.
瞎说
Liar.
也许你该考虑一下回去上学
Perhaps you should think about going back to school.
把你的生活搞得正常一点
A bit of normality in your life.
我不想回去上学
I'm not going back to school.
癌症晚期应该振作一些
There's got to be some perks to terminal illness.
我烦死你了吧？
I'm killing you, right?
每天都是
Every day.
看着点，哥们
Watch out, mate.
臭傻逼
Bloody idiot.
这家伙要干吗？
What's this guy up to?
泰萨，你干吗去啊？泰萨？
Tessa, where are you going? Tessa?
泰萨！
Tessa!
骑摩托车的感觉
That was good.
真不错
A ride on a motorbike.
这事应该在我的癌症清单上
Should have been on my list.
都什么呀？说一个听听
What is? Name one.
出名
Fame.
你要多出名啊？
How famous do you want to be?
名气大到能让全世界的人都停下手里的事
Enough for the whole world to stop what it's doing
在我死前排着队来跟我道别
and personally come and say goodbye to me when I die.
我觉得这挺好，你的要求还不是太过分
I think it's good you're not asking too much there.
我只想让自己名扬在外，你知道么
I just want to have my name out there somewhere, you know.
你不用担心，人们不会忘了你的，泰丝
You don't have to worry about being forgotten, Tess.
还有呢？
Anything else?
还有
Yeah.
你干吗呀？
What are you doing?
我正在想另外一个
I just thought of another.
你不会是要裸泳吧
You're not gonna swim naked.
不是，你以为我疯了吗？
No way. You think I'm crazy?
不是全脱
Not naked.
泰丝！泰丝！
Tess! Tess!
好吧，数到三，行吗？
Okay, count of three, yeah?
什么？
What?
咱们必须得跑进去，全都没到水里才行
Just got to commit. We just run in, full whack.
就这么定了，来吧
Deal. Right.
妈的来呀
Bollocks. - Here we go.
一，二，三！
One, two, three!
你这个坏人！你太缺德了！
You're evil! You are so evil!
感觉怎么样？
How is it?
特别好，实际上水里又暖和又舒服
Yeah, actually really gorgeous and lovely.
真的？
Really?
不是。不过你也下来吧
No. But go for it anyway.
来呀，怕什么？
Come on, what are you scared of?
没什么
Nothing.
好吧，好吧
Okay, okay.
看，往好的方向说
See, the great thing is,
我总是在想
I have actually always wondered
怎么才能穿着袜子把它晾干
if it was possible to dry yourself with a sock.
谢谢你陪我
Thanks for doing that with me.
我可不想错过这种事
I wouldn't have missed it for the world.
星星出来了
The stars are out.
是啊
Yeah.
你看见上面那五颗星了吗？
See that group of five up there?
排成弧形的那些
The kind of curved shape.
看见了吗？看见了吗？
See them? See them?
看见了
Yeah.
我根本不知道它叫什么
I've got no idea what they're called.
笨蛋
Goon.
不
No.
什么？
What?
对不起
I'm sorry.
你不喜欢我？
Don't you like me?
不是因为那个
It's not that.
我觉得我承受不起
I don't think I can handle it.
回见
I'll see you around.
泰丝……泰丝，等等
Tess... Tess, wait. Come on.
泰丝，别这样
Tessa, come on.
不，我犯了个错误
No, I've made a mistake.
什么？什么错误？
What? What mistake?
你救不了我
You can't save me.
在你小时候
When you were a baby,
我跟你妈躺在你旁边看着你喘气
me and your mum used to lie awake at night watching you breathe.
我们当时都很担心如果我们不看着你
We were convinced that if we stopped looking,
你就会忘了怎么呼吸
you'd forget how to do it.
等你的孩子长大之后，那就是另外一种担心
As your kids get older, it's a different kind of worry.
我们永远都在担心
It never ever goes.
你想想吧
Please think about that.
你知道么，我更喜欢你跟我胡扯
You know, I kind of prefer it when you give me shit.
泰萨？
Tessa?
护士！
Nurse!
拿着，亲爱的
Here, darling.
好的，好的
Okay, okay.
我们很快把这打扫干净
We'll soon have that cleared up.
对不起，对不起
I'm sorry. Sorry.
没事，亲爱的
It's okay, darling.
你好，泰萨，感觉怎么样？
Hello, Tessa. How are you?
还行
Good.
我觉得我对自己的估价太高了
I think dignity's overrated anyway.*
我们昨晚做了一些化验
We performed some tests last night.
恐怕癌细胞已经蔓延到你的脊髓了
I'm afraid the cancer has spread to your spinal fluid.
扩散的速度比我们预想的要快
Things are progressing more quickly than we first thought.
你的病情急转直下
You've moved further down the line.
有多急？
How much further?
我想说的是，想干点什么就去干吧
I would encourage you to do the things you want to do.
我尽力吧
I'm trying.
多迷人的花园啊！
Enchanted Garden!
喔！
Whoo!
真好看
That was lovely.
没劲，在放个别的
Boring. Do another.
你想放什么？要不放个火箭？
What do you want to do? Should I do a rocket?
好哇！放个火箭！
Yes! Do a rocket!
好
Okay.
再跟我说一遍你干吗来了
Remind me again why you're here.
你爸爸说我要是再不露个脸就把我腿砍下来
Your father said he'd chop my legs off if I didn't show up.
大家准备好了吗？
Ready, everybody?
捂住耳朵，这个特别响
Cover your ears, this is gonna be aloud one.
哦！
Oh!
好吧
Okay.
好吗？
Okay?
好
Okay.
不错，你那还有什么呀？
Not bad. What else you got in there?
要不我再放个二十一响小瀑布？
Should I go for a 21-shot Cascade?
好哇！放小瀑布！我数着
Yes, do the Cascade! I'll count.
准备好了吗？好，走你
Ready? Right, here we go.
一，二，三
One, two, three...
三……
Three...
四……四，五……
- Four...- Four, five...
六，七，八，九，十
six, seven, eight, nine, 10.
泰萨……
Tessa...
最坏的情况是什么？
What's the worst that can happen?
会很疼
It'll hurt.
已经挺疼的了
It already hurts.
邹逸说的对。这能让我活下去
Zoey was right. I'm alive.
我还活着
I'm alive.
早晨好，爸爸，睡得好吗？
Morning, Dad. Sleep well?
你是谁？你跟我对我女儿干吗了？
Who are you? What have you done with my daughter?
坐下
Sit.
吃，喝咖啡
Eat. Drink coffee.
爸爸，我想给你介绍一下
Dad, I want to introduce someone.
哦，天呐
Oh, God.
这是亚当，亚当，这是我爸爸
This is Adam. Adam, Dad.
见到您很高兴，先生
It's good to meet you, sir.
你不用管他叫先生
You don't have to call him sir.
叫先生挺好的
Sir will be fine.
很好，谁要烤面包？
Excellent. Who wants toast?
你可以走了
You can go.
那不就错过好玩的了么？
And miss all the fun?
没事，你走吧，泰丝
It's all right, Tess.
坐下。-好
Sit down. -Yeah.
作为一个父亲，当女儿带回来一个男孩
It's a terrible day in an man's life
将是很糟糕的一天
when his daughter brings a boy home.
我老觉得要是我把第一个给宰了，其他人知道了就不敢再来了
I always thought if I killed the first one, word would get around.
你上大学了吗？
Do you go to college?
上了一阵子
Yeah, I had a place.
后来家里出了点儿事儿，你知道
Then some stuff happened, you know.
我知道出什么事了，对你的不幸我感到很遗憾
I know what happened. I'm sorry for your loss.
是啊
Yeah.
你妈妈怎么样了？
How is your mum doing?
有时候还行。-是吧
Some days she seems okay. -Yeah.
我曾经想过泰萨
I used to think that about Tessa.
你知道她的情况吧？
You're aware of her condition?
知道，她什么都跟我说了
Yeah, she's told me everything.
不，她没有
No, she hasn't.
如果她想让你看到她的迷人之处
If she wants you to find her attractive,
她就不会把所有的事都告诉你
then one thing she won't have done is told you everything.
你多大了？
How old are you?
问这干吗？
Why?
因为以你这个岁数，不用非得去照顾别人
Because at your age, you shouldn't have to be nursing someone.
泰萨不需要照顾
Tessa doesn't need nursing.
不，她需要
Yes, she does.
她的情况会越来越糟
And she will more and more.
而你，我的小朋友，你承担不了那么繁重的工作
And you, my young friend, you're simply not up to the task.
那，你为什么不帮我们个忙呢
So, why don't you do us all a favor,
趁她还活着的时候赶紧滚蛋
and piss off out of what's left of her life.
你是怎么从你爸那把车借出来的？
So, how'd you get your dad to lend you the car?
我还以为你再也不理他了呢
I thought you weren't speaking to him.
我还有一个理由没用呢
I knew there was a reason I forgot to ask.
好吧，谢谢你带我来
Well, thanks for bringing me.
我还以为会有好多女孩
I thought it would be full of girls
拿着纸巾准备受伤呢
holding tissues and looking gutted.
至少斯科特私下里给了我钱
At least Scott paid for privacy.
他会度过这一关的
He'll get over it.
不，不会的
No, never.
他永远都过不去了，他恨我
He never will. He hates me.
你恨我吗？
Do you?
我今天跟他们谈了
I'm just talking to them today.
关于下一次约会？
About making another appointment?
是啊，我不想要，行吗？
Yes. Yeah, I want it gone, all right?
邹逸·沃克？我们准备好了
Zoey Walker? We're ready for you now.
我不想要
I just want it gone.
你撞到围栏了
You hit that curb.
又不是我的错。这条路应该是直的
Wasn't my fault. The road should have been straight.
你到了
There you go.
泰丝，你知道我没得选的
Tess, you know I've got no choice.
你都不知道你自己在说什么
You don't even know what those words mean.
既然你这么反对干吗还要陪我去？
Why did you come if you were just going to disapprove?
因为你需要我陪你
'Cause that's why you asked me.
嘿
Hey.
你好。这是我第一次开车
Evening. That was my first drive.
第一次开？
First ever?
你可真是想起一出是一出啊
Well, then you did fantastic.
你觉得如何？
You think?
是啊，挺好，就是换挡的时候声音太大了
Yeah. Yeah, that's just how changing gear is meant to sound.
这是我爸爸的车，它活该这样
It's my dad's car.Deserves what it gets.
他只是想尽量保护你的安全
He's just trying to keep you safe.
我觉得根本用不着，你说呢？
I think that ship has sailed, don't you?
你想跟我约会吗？
Would you like to go on a date with me?
我只是觉得我们从来没约会过
Just it occurred to me we've never
应该正式约一次
actually been on a date,like a proper one,
而且我觉得咱们应该试试
and I thought that maybe we should.
知道么，其实用不着非得在今天晚上，比如现在，
You know, it doesn't have to be right tonight, like now,
但是，你知道，这个邀请随时都有效
but, you know, the offer's there, for anytime.
你只要告诉我什么时间合适就行了
You just let me know when suits.
现在就行
Now is good.
天呐，泰萨，你之前应该来个电话
Christ, Tessa. You could have called.
你在这干吗？
What are you doing here?
你爸和卡尔到处找你，你到哪去了？
Dad and Cal are looking for you. Where have you been?
咱们改天再聊吧
We'll have to talk about it some other time.
为什么？
Why?
因为我得去赴一个约会
'Cause I've got a date.
对，她回来了
Yeah. She's here.
今晚不行，今晚可不能犯病
Not tonight. Please, not tonight.
行了，我跟你爸说了，我告诉他不用担心，他……
Okay, I've called your father. I've told him not to worry. He's going...
我的天呐！-只是流鼻血而已
Oh, my God. -It's just a nosebleed.
不是吧，你的血都快流干了，泰萨，我……
No, it's pumping out of you. Tessa, I...
我该怎么办？-我不知道……
What should I do? -I don't know...
给，拿这毛巾
Here, take a towel.
坐下，捏捏鼻子什么的
Sit down. Pinch your nose or something.
哦，你得去医院
Oh, you need to go to hospital.
一会血就不流了。我得给你爸打电话
It'll stop in a minute. I'm calling your father.
我该给你爸打电话吗？我该怎么办啊
Should I call your father? I don't know what to do.
告诉我该干什么！ -给我拿点冰块来
Tell me what to do! -Just get me some ice.
什么？ -冰块！
What? -Ice!
最好是一带冻豌豆
A bag of frozen peas would be best.
对，冻豌豆
Right. Frozen peas.
这有甜玉米，甜玉米行吗？
There's sweet corn. Is sweet corn okay?
哦，天呐
Oh, Jesus.
你还是带我去医院吧
You have to take me to hospital.
我不行，泰萨，我觉得应该让你爸带你去
I can't, Tessa. I think your father should do this.
来不及了
There isn't time.
好吧
Okay.
是的，叫辆救护车，谢谢，快点，快点！
Yes. Ambulance, please. Quickly. Quickly!
那是谁？-不
Who is it? -No.
那是谁？-他不能……
Who is it? -He can't...
我需要帮助。-别让他进来
I need help. -Don't let him in.
不行，我需要帮手
No, I need help.
他不能看见我这样
He can't see me like this!
泰丝，我自己干不了，我需要帮手
Tess, I can't do this on my own. I need help.
进来
Coming.
帮我把她抬到楼下去
Help me get her downstairs.
快点，你帮不帮忙？
Come on. Are you gonna help?
让他出去，求你了
Get him out! Please.
好吧，你走吧，我们能处理，走
All right, just go.We can manage. Go.
给你拿着这个好吗？
Would you hold that?
谢谢你
Thank you.
亚当
Adam.
她肯定会很渴，她流了好多血
She must be thirsty. She's lost so much blood.
要不要给她喝点水？用不用？
Should she have some water? Should she?
还是让医生来看看吧，好吗？
Let's see what the doctor says, all right.
很好，到这来
Good. Here you are.
好，以前有没有血小板减少的症状？
Right. Any signs of thrombocytopenia before today?
孩儿她妈？孩儿她妈？
Mum? Mum?
抱歉，问我呐？
Sorry, me?
她有没有抱怨过头疼？
Has she complained of a headache?
你有没有注意到什么她注射过毒品？
Have you noticed any pinprick bruising?
说实话，我没注意
I didn't look, to be honest.
她最后一次输血是什么时候？
When was the last platelet transfusion?
我不知道，我可以找人问问
I'm not sure. I can try...I can try and find out.
她最近有没有用过什么阿司匹林之类的药？
Has she used any aspirin products recently?
我不知道，我不知道
I don't know. I don't...
对不起，这些问题我一个都答不上来
I'm sorry. I don't know the answers to any of these questions.
我最后一次血小板输血是五月十八号
My last platelet transfusion was May 18th.
好的，谢谢你，别说话了
Okay, thank you. Don't talk.
孩儿她妈，过来，握住你女儿的手
Mum, get yourself round here, and hold your daughter's hand.
好，捏你妈妈的手，一次是：是，两次是：否
Okay. Squeeze your mum's hand once for yes, twice for no.
明白了吗？别说话
Understand? Don't talk.
是
Yes.
有没有血小板减少症？头疼？瘀伤？
Any signs of thrombocytopenia? Headaches? Bruising?
否
No.
阿司匹林类药？宝治灵？替钾？消炎药？
Aspirin products? Bonjela? Teejel? Anti-inflammatories?
没有，一个都没有
No, none of those. No.
好
Good.
现在，恐怕我们要用灼伤性方式给你的鼻子消毒
Now I'm afraid we're going to need to cauterize your nose.
以前做过灼伤性消毒吗？-是的，她说做过
Have you been cauterized before? -Yes, she has.
好的，我们检查一下你的血小板
Okay. We'll check your platelets,
然后你需要输至少两个单位的血小板
and then you're going to need at least a couple of units.
今晚会很难过，不过你明天一早就可以回家了
A rough night, but you'll be back home tomorrow.
我们知道病症所在了
We got there in the end.
大夫说是晚期鼻子出血，你知道，严重的那种
They said it was a posterior nosebleed, the...You know, the bad kind.
他们给她的鼻子做了血管……
They had to pack her nose with vaso...
血管收缩术
Vasoconstrictive.
对，血管收缩药
Yeah, vasoconstrictive agents.
在那之前，输了两个单位的血，还做了血小板计数
And before they transfused in two units, they did a platelet count.
还有呢？
And?
稳定了
Stable.
你干得不错
You did well.
我在这，你要是有事的话可以走了
I'm here, you can go now if you want.
我能留下吗？
Can I stay?
当然了
Yeah.
你感觉怎么样？
How are you feeling?
困
Sleepy...
谢谢你能陪我
Thank you for being there.
我真是被你吓坏了，还有你的男朋友
It was a bit of a shock. For your boy, too.
我能理解
It was understandable.
那孩子真挺招人喜欢的，跟奶酥似的
He's a hot buttered biscuit, that one.
是啊，我也是这么形容他的
Yeah, that's exactly how I'd describe him.
你会怎么跟他说？
What would you say?
他要没跟我在一起，我就随便编个理由
When he's not with me, I think I've made him up.
他没再打电话或者跟到医院去吧？
He didn't call or come after us, or anything?
没有
No.
也许我应该骗他
Maybe I did make him up.
天呐
Good God.
怎么了？
What?
看那，在桥上
There, on the bridge.
真奇怪
That's odd.
到处都是你的名字，泰萨！
You're everywhere, Tessa!
是他干的
He's done it.
他把我的名字写得到处都是
He's put my name in the world.
杂耍棍！你给我买了杂耍滚！
Juggling clubs! You brought me juggling clubs!
生日快乐！
Happy birthday.
你会玩吗？
Can you do these?
会，会一点
Yeah. A bit, yeah.
你要是想学我待会教你
I'll help you practice later if you want.
爸爸，亚当能留下吃晚饭吗？
Dad, can Adam stay for dinner?
不行
No.
妈妈
Mum...
我又不住在这，说了不算吧？
I don't live here, do I?
谢谢你
Thank you.
不过还是让他留下吧
But let him stay.
你们串通好了的
It's a conspiracy.
好吧，我表演个魔术
All right,on with the magic show.
挑一张牌
Pick a card.
红桃五
Five of hearts.
不是
No.
总有一天我能猜出来
One day I'll get the right one,
你们都是废物
and you'll all crap yourselves.
哦，好哇，你现在都能说脏话啦？
Oh, nice. He's allowed to say that, is he?
只能说“废物”
It's only "crap."
好了，又有一件事可以从清单上划掉了
Well, that's another one to cross off the list.
你那清单还剩多少？
How's the list going?
剩下的我觉得都不重要了
Things I thought mattered don't matter so much anymore.
你怎么样？有什么计划吗？
How about you? Got anything you wanna put up there?
我还行
I'm fine.
我意思是，我有点……
I mean, there are things I've kind of,
你知道，选择对我来说……
you know, opted out of I guess.
不，我跟你还不一样
No, I'm not like you like that.
我不能……
I don't...
亚当？
Adam?
啊
Yeah.
你的生活还要继续
You've got to get in the game.
所以好好想想
So have a think.
你将来想干吗？你的梦想是什么？
What are your hopes,your dreams?
现在就说？
Right now?
对
Yeah.
松开我的手，松开
Let go of my hand. Let go of my hand.
我会松开的
I'll wipe out.
好吧，我会在你周围看着的
Yeah, but I'll be miles away.
来吧，自己试试，身体前倾往前滑就行了
Go on, all the way across. Just lean forward and run.
你能行的
You can do it.
前倾往前走，明白了
Lean and run, got it.
滑起来！泰萨·斯科特来啦！
Get in! Tessa Scott is in the house!
卡尔，怎么停下来啊？
Cal, how do you stop?
撞墙
Use the wall.
卡尔！-扶墙！
Cal! -Use the wall!
嘿，宝贝
Hi, babe.
嘿
Hey.
你滑得不错
You looked good out there.
我老摔跤，现在屁股还疼呢
I kept falling down.My bum hurts.
你应该弄点冰冷敷一下
You should put some ice on it.
我想把孩子生下来
I'm keeping the baby.
真的？
Really?
对呀，生下来
Yeah. Yes.
是个女孩，我将有个女儿了
It's a girl. I'm having a girl.
我给她起了个名字叫劳伦
And I'm gonna call her Lauren.
我想要这个孩子
That's what I'm gonna do.
你生的时候我想去看看
I want to be there.
你要是不想让我进产房
If you don't want me in the birth,
我就在外边，等你生完了我再看
then I can sit outside and come in afterwards.
我想当世界上第一个
I want to be one of the first people
抱你孩子的人
in the world to ever hold your baby.
还有五个月才生呢
It's five months away.
这不就有目标了么
Then it's something to aim for.
你看，很多人觉得下雪很美
You see, some people would find this beautiful.
但是在我看来，这就是在屠杀我那些可怜的蔬菜
But all I can think is, it's killing my poor vegetables.
嘿，想什么呢，泰丝？
Hey, what's up, Tess?
我并不满足，对于我们，和这些美景
It's not enough. Us. This.
你的意思是？
How do you mean?
跟我在一起，和我一起住之类的
Stay with me. Stay the nights.
你想让我做什么，泰丝？
What do you want from me, Tess?
晚上，一起睡觉，早上一块起床，一起吃早饭
Nighttime. Sleeping together.Waking up together. Breakfast.
你真正想要的是什么？
What do you really want?
我想让你在黑暗里陪着我
I want you to be with me in the dark.
抱着我
To hold me.
一直爱我
To keep loving me.
在我害怕的时候安慰我
To help me when I get scared.
陪着我一直到最后看看会发生什么
To come right to the edge and see what's there.
要是我理解错了怎么办？
What if I get it wrong?
你不会理解错的
It's impossible to get wrong.
送给你的
For you.
这是雪天使
It's a snow angel.
不行，不行，不行
No. No, no and no.
爸爸……-这是你清单上的吗？
Dad... -Is this on the list?
让一个男孩子跟你一块住？想都别想，不可能
A boy staying over? Forget it. No.
要知道，这请求我问出来都挺难的
You know, this is not easy for me to ask.
但是回答起来很容易
Well, it's very easy for me to answer.
我还以为有商量的余地呢。-这事没得商量
I thought you wanted to talk. -Not about this.
我不同意。讨论结束
I won't permit it.End of discussion.
别这么独裁行么
Don't pull rank on me.
我就独裁了，我是你爸爸
I have rank. I'm your father.
当不了多久了
Not for much longer.
准备好了吗？
Are you ready?
太远了
It's too far.
你就跳吧
Just jump.
太他妈远了
It's too bloody far.
那就别来了
Good night then.
等会
Wait.
你干吗呢？
What are you doing?
给自己打气啊
Psyching myself up.
哦，那还且着呢吧
Oh, is that gonna take a while,
我想去泡杯茶
'cause I quite fancy a cup of tea.
我的天呐
Oh, my God.
你没事吧？-我有事！
Are you all right? -No.
我摔着胳膊了
I've broken my arm.
俩胳膊都摔着了
Both arms.
我浑身都摔坏了
I've broken everything.
嗨。-嗨
Hi. -Hi.
噢
Ow.
但是你进来了
But you're here.
他在你房间里，对吧？
He's in there, isn't he?
是啊
Yes.
我不是跟你说了不行的吗
I told you I didn't want that.
我知道
I know.
你知道为什么吗？
You know why?
我知道
I think so.
他是个好孩子，泰萨
He's a good kid, Tessa.
但他只是个孩子，你不能全依赖他
But a kid is all he is. You can't rely on him.
他可能会让你失望的
He might let you down.
他不会的
He won't.
如果他会呢？
What if he does?
那我不是还有你呢吗，就像以前一样
Then I'll still have you. Like always.
这个太他妈好吃了
These are insanely good.
我觉得他这洋葱炸过了
I think they fry the onions in hair oil.
因为咱们值得
Because we're worth it.
我也想学打水漂儿
I wish I could do that.
你不会吗？
You can't?
不会
No.
我能让它漂两次，之后就不行了
I can do like two and then they just die.
我教你
I'll teach you.
我把它列进我的清单里去
I'll put it on my new list.
还有什么？
Along with what?
还有好多别的事
Too many things.
春天，水仙花和郁金香
Spring. Daffodils and tulips.
一次火车旅行
A long train journey.
看孔雀
A peacock.
在床上吃早餐
Bed and breakfast.
一大笔银行存款
A joint bank account.
年复一年地听你打呼噜
Listening to you snore for years and years.
我不打呼噜，我打吗？
I don't snore. Do I snore?
等你老了就会打的
You will when you get old.
为人父母，而且我们的孩子是个天才
To go to a parents' evening, and our child's a genius.
实际上，咱们将有三个孩子
Actually, all three of our kids.
咱们有三个孩子？
We're having three?
切斯特，玛丽莲和黛茜
Chester, Merlin and Daisy.
上帝保佑他们
God help them.
跟你在一起，跟你在一起
Being with you. Being with you.
跟你在一起
Being with you.
就跟你在一起
Just being with you.
这么说，是爱情的力量把你治愈了吗？
So, is the love cure still working its magic?
这得你说
You tell me.
我应该把这方法告诉我的病人们
I should recommend it to all my patients.
太好了！我收到短信了
Yes! I got a text.
卡尔有了个新手机
Cal's got a mobile phone.
他长大了
He's growing up.
五岁组赢了！
Year Five won!
公园里打水仗的游戏
There was a water fight in the park
五岁组对七岁组，五岁的赢了！
against Year Seven, and we won!
卡尔，跟菲利帕说说你最近都在忙什么呢
Cal, tell Philippa what you've been doing recently.
哦，好哇，我最近在玩“装死”的游戏
Oh, yeah. I'm doing "keep death away" spells.
我把大蒜挂在门上
I've put garlic above all the doors
还有泰萨床的四角
and at the four corners of Tessa's bed.
这么弄虽然挺恶心的，不过我觉得……
Which is pretty bloody gross, but I figure...
怎么了？
What?
What is it?
泰萨？
Tessa?
你爸爸呢？
Where's your father?
他跟我妈妈说了些什么，他说什么了？
Telling my mum something. What's he telling her?
咱们等他们来了再说，好吗？
Let's wait for them to join us, shall we?
得病的是我，不是他们
It's me that's sick, not them.
我到什么程度了，告诉我吧？
How sick, please?
你最新的血细胞测试数量很低
Your latest blood counts are very low.
你的免疫系统正在衰退
Your immune system is in collapse.
癌细胞已经扩散到全身了
The cancer is now everywhere.
我还有多长时间？
How much longer do I have?
我不想预测这个时间
I don't want to be drawn into time scales.
你说错了我不会告你的
I won't sue you if you're wrong.
我好朋友的预产期是四月
My best friend's due in April.
我还能坚持到孩子出生吗？
Will I get to meet her baby?
不能
No.
亚当？
Adam?
亚当在吗？
Is Adam here?
哦，他不在，抱歉，他得晚上才能回来呢
Oh, no, I'm sorry, darling. He won't be back till this evening.
来不及了，他去哪了？
That's too late. Where's he gone?
他上火车了，去参加接待日
He's on the train. For the Open Day.
接待日？-对，大学入学的接待日
Open Day? -Yeah, at the university.
听说他九月份要去上大学
I was so thrilled when he said he was
我真是太高兴了
taking up his place in September.
以前我还以为
There were times when I thought
我们得再等上一年呢
we'd be waiting another 12 months.
谁也不想当班上岁数最大的学生，是吧？
No one wants to be the oldest kid in the class, do they?
是啊，没有人愿意那样
No. No one wants that.
泰萨？
Tessa?
泰萨，你在吗？
Tessa, are you here?
亲爱的
Darling?
不
No.
你这个怪物
You monster.
你能不能给我留点好印象啊？
Do you want to leave me with nothing?
这就是你那份清单吗？
Is this it? The list.
一直就在这写着
It was here all along.
你以前为什么不给我看？
Why didn't you show me?
你应该给我看看
You should've shown me.
这上边有些事我帮不了你
Some of these,I could've helped you.
我真的很想帮你
I just wanted to help you.
可是我帮不了你
I couldn't help you.
我帮不了你
I can't help you.
我不想让你死
I don't want you to go.
我承担不了
I can't bear it.
让我跟你一块死吧
Take me with you.
哦，求你了
Oh, please...
我不想让你死
I don't want you to go.
哦，宝贝……
Oh, baby...
噢，我的宝贝……
Oh, you're my baby...
天呐，泰萨，我找你一天了
Jesus, Tess,I've been looking all over.
你来了多久了？
How long have you been up here?
你为什么不告诉我？
Why didn't you tell me?
你不能走那么远的路知道吗？
You can't be making that walk, right?
跟我回去吧，好吗
Just come back with me, please.
你为什么不告诉我？
Why didn't you tell me?
因为我
Because it's gonna be me!
因为最后留下的那个人是我
It's gonna be me that's left behind on my own.
你还敢说
Don't you dare feel sorry for yourself
你是最后留下的那个
because you get to stay behind.
甭跟我说着个！
Don't you fucking dare!
这才是你想要的
This is what you wanted.
我知道，这就是你想看到的
Come on, I know it. This is what you wanted.
你想让我往前走……
For me to go on and...
哦，你得理解我
Oh, please, you've got to know that
要不是因为你，
if it wasn't for you, I wouldn't be able
我哪也不会去，什么也不会干的
to go anywhere or do anything.
除了，也许除了我们在院子里认识的那天
Except, I don't know, fucking garden.
这一天迟早会来的
It's going to happen.
我知道
I know.
快了
Soon.
好吗？
All right?
大学里怎么样？
So what was it like there?
很大，有好多楼，我差点迷路
Big, lots of buildings.I got a bit lost.
咱们会想出办法的
We'll figure it out.
会吗？-会的
We will? -Yeah.
我会托生在别人身上的
I'm coming back as somebody else.
我会变成一长发女孩，在重生的第一天就去找你
I'll be the wild-haired girl that walks up to you on day one,
然后问你在学什么
and ask what you're studying.
然后我们会一见钟情
And I'll fall in love with you at first sight.
第二次一见钟情
Again.
跟我说说我会怎么样吧
Tell me how it will be.
从现在开始你会不想吃东西
You won't want to eat much from now on.
你会很渴
You'll be thirsty.
而且可能会发烧
And sometimes feverish.
你的睡眠时间会减少
You'll want to sleep a lot.
你的体力会渐渐丧失
You'll have little or no energy.
会疼吗？
Will it hurt?
不会，吗啡会让你感觉不到任何疼痛
No. The morphine will make sure you're not in any pain.
那会让你做很多美梦
It will give you some beautiful dreams.
嗨
Hi, there.
我老是想着看看你的孩子
I keep thinking I've met your baby.
她怎么样？
How is she?
特别好
Gorgeous.
会很爱她的
You'll love her.
这是真的吗？
Is this happening?
是啊
Yeah.
我现在都分不清真假了
I don't know what's real.
我能
I am.
你觉得我会害怕吗？
Do you think I'll be scared?
我觉得你运气好差啊
I think you've had the worst luck in the world,
如果我是你，我肯定会害怕
and if I was in your shoes, I would be scared.
但是我也相信，你会撑过最后这几天的
But I also believe that however you handle these last few days
你会就此无憾
will be exactly as it should be done.
我就烦你说“剩下几天”这种话
I hate it when you say days.
很快你的意识就会模糊
Quite soon you'll start to drift in and out of consciousness.
有时候你连说话都困难
Sometimes you won't be able to respond,
但是你会感觉到周围的人，能听见他们说话
but you'll know people are there, you'll hear them talk.
谢谢你能一直陪着她
Thank you for staying with her.
我爱她
I love her.
最后，泰丝，你的灵魂就飘走了
And eventually, Tess, you'll just drift away.
你还有别的问题吗？
Do you have any other questions?
没有了
No. No.
你醒了
You're awake.
我想吃一根冰棍
Just getting an ice lolly.
你按个铃我给你拿多好？
Why didn't you ring the bell?
还在找治疗方案呐？
Still looking for a cure?
能有点安慰
Pain relief.
我能用会儿电脑吗？
Can I use the computer for a sec?
行啊，当然了
Yeah. Of course.
不，你别起来
No, you're good.
你的头发长出来了
Your hair's growing back.
还不够快
Not quick enough.
你要给我看什么？
What are you showing me here?
一个更好的去处
A better site for you.
工作
Jobs.
你得开始想想了
You've got to start thinking.
现在不想
Not yet.
你得重新开始生活
You're gonna have a life again.
我从来没有自己的生活
I never had a life.
我是个会计
I was an accountant.
但是现在，你什么都能做
And now you can do anything.
我告诉泰萨和爸爸，
I'm telling Tessa and Dad,
还有所有我认识的人
and then everyone else I know.
我没有。-妈妈喜欢威尔莫特先生
Because I don't. -Mum fancies Mr. Wilmot.
我没有，我从来没这么说过
I do not. I never said that.
你说了，你说了
You did, you did.
妈妈喜欢威尔莫特先生
Mum fancies Mr. Wilmot.
所有的妈妈都喜欢威尔莫特先生
All the mums fancy Mr. Wilmot.
还有一些父亲也喜欢他
And a few of the dads.
嘿，你感觉怎么样？
Hey. How are you feeling?
你去哪了？
Where have you been?
我参加了一个家长教学会
I have been to a parent-teacher meeting.
你去啦？
You went to that?
她去了
She did. Yeah.
太他妈没劲了
And it bored the hole off me.
除了威尔莫特先生？
Except for Mr. Wilmot?
他说我干得不错，所以妈妈给我买了这个
He said I was doing great, so Mum got me this.
把它甩起来那声音就跟唱歌似的
You spin it round and it kind of sings.
对，但是别在屋里玩儿行吗？
Yeah,but not in the house, right?
你怎么起来了？
How come you're up?
出汗了吗？
Are you sweating?
我去把你的床单换一下
I'll change your sheets for you.
我去吧
I'll do it.
我会铺床
I can make a bed.
你要是知道就不会在医院被折叠床夹到屁股了
You wouldn't know a hospital corner if it bit you on the arse.
胡说八道
That is not true.
好吧，我出去玩
Fine, I'll do it outside.
来呀，泰萨，这玩意甩起来真的像唱歌一样
Come and have a listen, Tess. It kind of sings.
我这就来
I'm coming.Be there in a second.
不会有事的
It's gonna be all right.
亚当！
Adam!
哦，好
Yes, beautiful.
别让我掉下去。-我在这呢
Don't let me fall. -I've got you.
我在往下掉
I'm falling.
你没有，你没往下掉
You're not falling. You're not falling.
时刻……
Moments...
我们的生命是由一连串的时刻组成的
Our life is a series of moments.
每一个时刻都通往一个结果
Each one a journey to the end.
随他们去吧
Let them go.
都随他们去吧
Let them all go.
你应该道个别
You should say goodbye, Cal.
不
No.
别这样，亲爱的，这很重要
Come on, love, it's important.
我一说她可能就死了
It might make her die.
不会的，好吗？
Nothing you say can make her die. Okay?
嘿，我们都在这儿，泰萨
Hey, we're all here, Tessa.
我们都非常爱你
We all love you so much.
你干得棒极了
You've done so well.
你可以去了，去吧
You can go now. You can go.
再见，泰丝
Bye, Tess.
让你的灵魂来找我吧，我不怕了
Haunt me if you like. I don't mind.
我们的生活是由一连串的时刻组成的
Our life is a series of moments.
随他们去吧
Let them go.
时刻……
Moments...
这一次全都汇聚在这个房间里
All gathering to wards this one.
Clinging to me
Like a last breath you would breathe
You were like home to me
I don't recognize the street
Please don't close your eyes
Don't know where to look without them
Outside the cars speed by
I never heard them until now
I know you care
I know
it is always been there
But there's trouble ahead,
I can feel it
You are just saving
yourself when you hide it
Yeah, I know you care
I see it in the way you stare
As if there was trouble
ahead and you knew it
I'll be saving myself
from the ruin
And I know you care
I used to run down the stairs
To the door
and I thought you were there
Do you shape
through the comfort of us
Two lovers loved out of love
Oh, but I know you care
I know
it is always been there
But there's trouble ahead,
I can feel it
You are just saving
yourself when you hide it
Yeah, I know you care
I see it in the way you stare
As if there was trouble
ahead and you knew it
I'll be saving myself
from the ruin
And know it wasn't
always wrong
But I've never known
a winter so cold
Now I don't warm my hands
in your coat
But I still hope
'Cause this is how things
ought to have been
And I know the worst of it
wasn't all that it seemed
Why can't I dream
'Cause I know you care
And I know you care
I know you care
I know it's always
been there